Phone: (801) 709-0238
mathews.kyle@gmail.com
http://kyle.mathews2000.com

Kyle Mathews

Summary

An elite Drupal developer with a deep knowledge of open source software development, the education space, and collaborative software.

Passionate about finding elegant solutions to difficult problems. Experienced entrepreneur, Drupal developer, and User Experience designer. Creative, risk taker, strong writer and communicator, experienced at public speaking.

Education

Brigham Young University

2009. M.S., Information Systems. 2009. B.S., Information Systems.

Experience

1st Technical Hire at MuirWebs

February 2011 - current

MuirWebs is an early stage startup I'm working with. I'm architecting and building a Drupal SaaS product.. I've setup an automated build system and am integrating automated testing using Jenkins. I'm designing and building a custom analytics solution. The Drupal product is built using advanced Drupal tools such as Features, Context, Views, a custom extensible theme based on HTML5 and CSS3, and a number of custom modules.

University online learning community

March 2008 - current

While a student at Brigham Young University, I built an online community learning website to enable better collaboration between students and professors. Over 1000 students, alumni, and professors use Island. The site is built using Drupal and makes heavy use of the modules Organic Groups, Spaces, and Context. An example group: island.byu.edu/drupal

Founder of Eduglu

January 2009 – March 2011

I founded Eduglu to productize the social learning technology work I was doing with Island. Eduglu was one of the first Drupal products to be released. Eduglu was downloaded over 600 times and has been successfully deployed at a number of different institutions including Brigham Young University and Georgia State University.

1

Skills Drupal

I have extensive experience building sophisticated custom Drupal websites. I'm familiar with all major (and many minor) Drupal site-building modules and have written dozens of custom modules including a module to generate custom notification emails for Symantec Connect, a module to capture and store sales leads, and a module that enforces business rules for creating reviews on an online marketplace.

2

I maintain a number of modules on drupal.org.

OG Mailinglist Many people prefer to participate online via email then through forums. This module integrates the functionality of an email list and forum within a Drupal site so people people can start and comment on discussions on a website through email.

Memetracker Enables you to create an entirely automated online news site on any subject.

Mixpanel Many Drupal sites need custom analytics. This module helps by integrating Drupal with the analytics company Mixpanel.

Family History Distro Many families have 100s of documents and photos from their parents and grandparents they'd like to share. This project is to provide a Drupal distro to simplify the process of collecting and sharing stories, letters, documents, and pictures about your family, past and present.

Other technologies

Front end HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Compass, jQuery, Javascript/CoffeeScript, AJAX

Programming languages PHP, Python, Java, Bash, Javascript/CoffeeScript

Public speaking

I have presented at a number of international education and technology conferences as well as many smaller conferences and meetups including:

"Building Advanced Social Networks at a Large U.S. University" Drupalcon DC 2009

"Introducing Eduglu, a new Drupal distribution for Higher Education" Teaching With Technology Idea Exchange 2010

"Building Social Networks for Learning" Ignite Salt Lake City 2009